Hello English learners and welcome to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎来到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
Erica, today we are really excited, right?
Erica，今天我们很兴奋，对吧？
Yeah, we've got a great lesson today, all about real English.
是的，今天我们有一节很棒的课，全是关于地道英语的。
Exactly, English that you hear in movies and TV shows.
没错，就是你在电影和电视节目中听到的英语。
Yeah, speaking of movies, today's podcast takes place at the movies.
说到电影，今天的播客场景就发生在电影院。
Exactly, and that's why it's so fun today.
没错，所以今天特别有趣。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
And so before we listen to our dialogue, let's take a look at our vocabulary preview.
在听对话之前，我们先来看看词汇预览。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
In today's vocabulary preview, we have two words.
今天的词汇预览有两个词。
And the first word is inconsiderate.
第一个词是inconsiderate。
Inconsiderate.
Inconsiderate。
So, Erica, what is it when someone is inconsiderate?
那么，Erica，当一个人inconsiderate是什么意思？
If someone's inconsiderate, they're not thinking about the feelings of other people.
如果一个人inconsiderate，就是他不考虑别人的感受。
Right.
对。
For example, yesterday, I was on the subway and it was full.
比如，昨天我坐地铁，车厢很挤。
Right.
对。
And an old lady was standing there and no one got up to give her their seat.
一位老太太站在那里，没有人站起来给她让座。
That was pretty inconsiderate.
那真是太不体贴了。
Great.
很好。
So now let's take a look at our second word and it's keep it down.
现在我们来看第二个词，keep it down。
Keep it down.
Keep it down。
So, why don't we listen to some examples on how we use keep it down so we can understand.
我们来听一些例子，看看keep it down怎么用，这样我们就能理解了。
Example one.
例子一。
Excuse me.
打扰一下。
Do you mind keeping it down?
你能小声点吗？
It's after midnight.
已经过了午夜了。
Okay.
好的。
Sorry.
抱歉。
Example two.
例子二。
I'm trying to study.
我正在学习。
Do you mind keeping it down?
你能小声点吗？
Example three.
例子三。
You mind keeping it down?
你能小声点吗？
I'm trying to watch the game.
我正在看比赛。
So that means be quiet.
所以那意味着安静点。
Yes.
是的。
Don't make so much noise.
别那么吵。
I used to hear this one all the time from my mother.
我以前经常从我妈妈那里听到这句话。
I think we all did when we were children.
我想我们小时候都听过。
Yeah.
是啊。
Okay.
好的。
So now let's listen to the dialogue for the first time.
现在让我们第一次听对话。
It's going to be kind of fast.
语速会有点快。
But don't worry about it if you can't understand everything.
但如果听不懂全部内容，别担心。
By the end of today's lesson, you will understand this dialogue.
到今天的课程结束时，你会理解这段对话的。
Those people in front of us are making so much noise.
我们前面那些人太吵了。
It's so inconsiderate.
真不体贴。
Don't worry about it.
别担心。
It's not such a big deal.
没什么大不了的。
I can't hear a thing.
我什么都听不见。
Excuse me.
打扰一下。
Can you keep it down?
能小声点吗？
Sure.
当然。
Sorry about that.
抱歉。
Someone's phone is ringing.
有人手机响了。
Honey, I think it's your phone.
亲爱的，我想是你的手机。
Did you forget to switch it off?
你忘记关了吗？
Oh no.
哦不。
You're right.
你说得对。
It's so embarrassing.
太尴尬了。
You mind keeping it down?
你能小声点吗？
I'm trying to watch a movie here.
我在这儿看电影呢。
I hate it when people's phones ring when I'm watching a movie.
我讨厌看电影时别人手机响。
I think everyone gets kind of angry, but we're going to talk about this a little bit later.
我想每个人都会有点生气，但我们稍后会讨论这个。
Why don't we take a look now at our language takeaway?
我们现在来看看语言要点吧？
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
So the language takeaway is our most important words for today's lesson.
语言要点是我们今天课程中最重要的词汇。
And our first word today is not such a big deal.
今天的第一个词是“没什么大不了的”。
Not such a big deal.
没什么大不了的。
So when something is not a big deal, it's not a big problem.
所以当某事不是什么大事时，就不是大问题。
It's not important, right?
不重要，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
Okay, let's listen to some examples.
好的，我们来听一些例子。
Example one.
示例一。
I can't get these files due by tomorrow.
我无法在明天之前完成这些文件。
It's okay.
没关系。
It's not such a big deal.
不是什么大不了的事。
Example two.
示例二。
I'm really sorry.
我真的很抱歉。
I'm going to be 10 minutes late for the meeting.
我开会要迟到10分钟。
It's not such a big deal.
不是什么大不了的事。
Peter and Liam are late too.
彼得和利亚姆也迟到了。
Now let's look at our second word and it's switch it off.
现在来看第二个词，是“关掉它”。
Switch it off.
关掉它。
So this word means to turn it off.
这个词的意思是把它关掉。
To turn something off.
把某物关掉。
Now we can use it in three different ways.
我们可以用三种不同的方式使用它。
Yeah, this one is a little bit complicated because it changes a little bit depending
是的，这个有点复杂，因为它会根据
on how you use it.
你如何使用而略有变化。
So Marco, I think you've got some examples for us.
那么马可，我想你给我们准备了一些例子。
Right.
对。
So for example, I can say, did you switch off your phone?
比如，我可以说，你关掉手机了吗？
Or you could say, did you switch your phone off?
或者你可以说，你把手机关掉了吗？
Right.
对。
Or simply you can ask, did you switch it off?
或者简单地问，你把它关掉了吗？
I think this one is a little bit hard.
我觉得这个有点难。
Let's look at a couple more examples.
我们再来看几个例子。
Okay.
好的。
So I can say, for example, switch off the TV.
比如，我可以说，关掉电视。
Switch the TV off.
把电视关掉。
Or switch it off.
或者把它关掉。
Yeah.
是的。
I think that's a little bit more clear.
我觉得这样更清楚一些。
Yeah.
是的。
But you know what?
但你知道吗？
We even had trouble with that one, didn't we?
我们连那个都搞不定，不是吗？
Yeah.
是的。
We had to do it a couple of times.
我们不得不重复了好几次。
Okay.
好的。
Now let's look at our last word and it's can't hear a thing.
现在来看最后一个词，是“什么也听不见”。
Can't hear a thing.
什么也听不见。
I can't hear a thing.
我什么都听不见。
Can't hear a thing.
什么都听不见。
Okay.
好的。
We have some examples for this phrase, so let's listen.
我们有一些这个短语的例子，我们来听一下。
Example one.
例子一。
What's going on in there?
里面发生什么事了？
I don't know.
我不知道。
I can't hear a thing.
我什么都听不见。
Example two.
例子二。
What?
什么？
I'm sorry.
对不起。
This music is too loud.
这音乐太吵了。
I can't hear a thing.
我什么都听不见。
So that's like saying, I can't hear.
所以这就像在说，我听不见。
Exactly.
没错。
I can't hear anything.
我什么都听不见。
It's too loud.
太吵了。
Right.
对。
So now we are ready to listen to our dialogue a second time.
现在我们准备好再听一遍对话了。
It's going to be slower.
这次会慢一些。
This time listen for some of the key words we were explaining.
这次注意听我们刚才解释的一些关键词。
Those people in front of us are making so much noise.
我们前面那些人太吵了。
It's so inconsiderate.
真不体谅人。
Don't worry about it.
别担心。
It's not such a big deal.
没什么大不了的。
I can't hear a thing.
我什么都听不见。
Excuse me.
打扰一下。
Can you keep it down?
能小声点吗？
Sure.
当然。
Sorry about that.
抱歉。
Someone's phone is ringing.
有人的手机响了。
Honey, I think it's your phone.
亲爱的，我想是你的手机。
Did you forget to switch it off?
你忘记关了吗？
Oh no.
哦不。
You're right.
你说得对。
That's so embarrassing.
太尴尬了。
Do you mind keeping it down?
能小声点吗？
I'm trying to watch a movie here.
我在这儿看电影呢。
Okay, great.
好的，很好。
Now with the dialogue slower, it's really understandable.
现在对话慢下来了，真的很容易理解。
Yeah, I think you could catch those key words a lot better.
是的，我觉得你能更好地抓住这些关键词。
Perfect.
完美。
So now we are ready to look at putting it together.
现在我们准备来看如何把它们组合起来。
Putting it together.
组合起来。
So in putting it together, we help you use a great phrase in different ways.
在组合部分，我们帮你用不同的方式使用一个很棒的短语。
And today's phrase is, do you mind?
今天的短语是，你介意吗？
Do you mind?
你介意吗？
Okay, so let's listen to some examples on how you can use this phrase in different situations.
好的，让我们听一些例子，看看如何在不同情况下使用这个短语。
Example one.
例子一。
Do you mind holding my coat for me?
你介意帮我拿一下外套吗？
Example two.
例子二。
Oh, I forgot my wallet.
哦，我忘带钱包了。
Do you mind paying for dinner?
你介意付晚餐钱吗？
Example three.
例子三。
Do you mind turning off your phone?
你介意关掉手机吗？
So this phrase is usually pretty polite.
所以这个短语通常很礼貌。
I could say to you, Marco, do you mind holding my coat for me?
我可以对你说，Marco，你介意帮我拿一下外套吗？
And that's really polite.
这非常礼貌。
Yeah.
是的。
So would you mind, do you mind are very polite phrases.
所以“would you mind”和“do you mind”是非常礼貌的短语。
But depending on your voice and how you use your tone, it could be a little bit sarcastic,
但根据你的声音和语调，它可能带点讽刺，
right?
对吧？
Yeah, it could be a little bit rude if you say, would you mind keeping it down?
是的，如果你说“你介意小声点吗？”可能会有点粗鲁。
Exactly.
没错。
Like we heard in our dialogue.
就像我们在对话中听到的那样。
Yeah.
是的。
So that's not so polite.
所以那就不太礼貌了。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，没错。
I mean, in English, you have to be careful because your tone of voice tells the other
我的意思是，在英语中，你必须小心，因为你的语调会告诉对方
person how you're feeling.
你的感受。
If you're angry, sad, or just like in any other language.
如果你生气、难过，或者就像其他语言一样。
Yeah, that's true.
是的，没错。
So I mean, using a phrase like, do you mind is a great phrase, but make sure you keep
所以我的意思是，使用像“你介意吗”这样的短语很棒，但一定要保持
a positive tone in your voice.
积极的语调。
Exactly.
没错。
So now that we've talked about all these great things, we can listen to the dialogue a third
现在我们讨论了所有这些好东西，我们可以第三次听对话了，
time, but it'll be at its normal speed.
但这次是正常语速。
Those people in front of us are making so much noise.
我们前面那些人太吵了。
It's so inconsiderate.
真不体贴。
Don't worry about it.
别担心。
It's not such a big deal.
没什么大不了的。
Oh, I can't hear a thing.
哦，我什么都听不见。
Excuse me.
打扰一下。
Can you keep it down?
能小声点吗？
Sure.
当然。
Sorry about that.
抱歉。
Someone's phone is ringing.
有人手机响了。
Honey, I think it's your phone.
亲爱的，我觉得是你的手机。
Did you forget to switch it off?
你忘记关了吗？
Oh no.
哦不。
You're right.
你说得对。
That's so embarrassing.
太尴尬了。
Do you mind keeping it down?
能小声点吗？
I'm trying to watch a movie here.
我在这儿看电影呢。
I'm sorry.
对不起。
So I know that in different countries, there are different habits about watching movies.
我知道在不同的国家，看电影的习惯也不同。
Yeah, that's definitely true.
是的，确实如此。
Erica, what's it like in Canada?
Erica，加拿大是什么情况？
Well in Canada, it's really common to eat popcorn and candy and maybe chips while you're
嗯，在加拿大，看电影时吃爆米花、糖果和薯片是很常见的。
watching a movie.
看电影。
But, if your phone rings in the movie theater, this is a big problem.
但是，如果你的手机在电影院响了，那是个大问题。
I imagine it is.
我想也是。
I mean, I would be upset also.
我的意思是，我也会不高兴。
What about in Ecuador?
厄瓜多尔呢？
Well, in Ecuador and in South America, usually people can bring in food from the outside.
嗯，在厄瓜多尔和南美洲，通常人们可以带外面的食物进来。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah, so it's not really uncommon, depending on the city, to find people bringing in chicken
是的，所以根据城市不同，看到有人带鸡肉
or some sort of like really smelly food.
或者某种味道很大的食物并不罕见。
No way!
不会吧！
So, you get either really hungry or really upset, but that's what happens.
所以，你要么非常饿，要么非常烦躁，但事情就是这样。
You know, I used to live in Switzerland, and in Switzerland you would have to eat before
你知道吗，我以前住在瑞士，在瑞士你得在
you watch the movie.
看电影之前先吃东西。
There was no popcorn, no soda, no candy inside the movie theater.
电影院里没有爆米花、没有汽水、没有糖果。
Can you imagine that?
你能想象吗？
I could not live with that because the whole purpose of going to the movies is to have
我可受不了，因为去看电影的全部意义就在于
some popcorn and relax and have a good time.
吃点爆米花，放松一下，享受美好时光。
You can't have a movie without popcorn.
没有爆米花就不算看电影。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay, so we've talked a lot about how to ask someone to be quiet today, and I hope that
好了，今天我们聊了很多关于如何让别人安静的话题，我希望
you'll go out and try a few of these phrases in your daily life.
你会在日常生活中尝试使用这些短语。
Yes, and I hope also that you visit our website at EnglishPod.com and leave all your questions
是的，我也希望你能访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，留下你的所有问题
and comments.
和评论。
Marco and I are there every day, so we'll be happy to answer your questions, but until
Marco 和我每天都在那里，所以我们很乐意回答你的问题，但在
next time, bye!
下次之前，再见！
Bye!
再见！